First, we choose a circle tool, click and drag your mouse in the 2D window to form a circle, press the Ctrl key to form a positive circle.
The widest part of this circle is twice as wide as your head.
After selecting this board, click the positioning key in the upper right corner, then click on the virtual model, you can arrange this board near the head of the virtual model.
This positioning symbol is like a handle, now the positioning ball is a double corner, you can see.
If we directly press the Ctrl key to simulate, this board will fall on the head of the virtual model, because we have gravity in the 3D environment.
We can return the gravity to 0 first, so that the gravity in the 3D space no longer works, and then let this hat stay above the head of the virtual model.
On the right side of the gravity, we adjust the value of gravity to 0,
and then look at the simulation, the 3D board will no longer have the influence of gravity.
In order to prevent the board from moving, we can temporarily fix it on the virtual model.
Here we can use a function under the fake needle, called the function of fixing to the virtual model.
Click on the board, then click on the head of the virtual model, this board will be fixed on the virtual model head, it will not move horizontally.
Next, we are going to make this hat hat.
For this hat, we can first select its outside panel line, and then click on the internal line border to draw an internal circle.
When we select this internal circle, the double center point will be retracted, and it will be retracted based on the center.
So we can adjust this internal circle, which is the size of the hole we are going to dig later.
The basis of the size of this hole is that when we switch to the virtual model front,
we want to see that this hole is slightly larger than its head.
After we finish, we can select this internal circle in the middle, and then right-click to cut and sew.
Then it will become the top of our hat later.
Next, we can arrange the position of this top of the hat in the 3D space,
to confirm how high this hat is, and then delete the excess internal line.
Of course, you can also use the cut directly just now.
Since the board is now cut open by us,
then we can redo it.
We can reuse the function of sewing to the virtual model,
and fix the outer circle of the hat on the virtual model head.
Because the current 3D window is still zero in weight,
so the top plate will float in the air.
But there is another problem when the weight is zero,
that is, when we adjust the plate, it cannot apply our adjustment very well.
So in the later stage of our production, we will adjust the weight back to the original value.
We will use the physical attribute to form such a lifting effect.
Now we switch to the editor tool.
Select this line, double-click,
so we can get the length of this whole circle.
It can be seen in the attribute editor.
Then we switch to the rectangular tool.
Its width is the width we just measured.
The height is the overall height of our hat.
I set it to 100 mm here.
Then we find the sewing line tool.
Use the line sewing to sew the plate and the plate in order.
First, we select the longest section,
and then press the Shift key to click in one direction.
Use the add to side to quickly arrange this plate near the hat plate,
and then freeze the top hat plate at the top.
Now the whole thing looks soft.
We can use the attribute editor to
increase the bending intensity of the material's physical properties.
When the bending intensity of the plate is increased,
it is not easy to break the plate,
and its own support is very strong.
Because now we are looking at the texture surface,
so we can see that this plate is facing the back.
Then we need to select this plate and right-click,
turn the surface over,
and let it rotate to the normal position.
Click on the icon here,
we can switch to the display type of the plate.
Then use the line sewing tool to sew the two sides together.
After sewing, this plate will hold up.
Then we activate the top of this plate,
and sew them together.
For sewing, we can refer to the direction of the sewing line
of the front and the side plates before.
First select the long side,
and then press the Shift key to click.
In the 3D environment,
we can check if the sewing line has an intersection.
If there is no intersection, you can press the model key,
that is, the control key, to simulate.
Then we need to set the folding angle of the sewing line
to form a folding effect of the nose.
First of all, it must be a straight angle when folding,
so we can try 90 degrees or 270 degrees first.
When we set 270 degrees,
a nose corner is formed here.
Because we set the sewing needle before,
so now the hat can't be removed.
So we need to use the edit sewing tool,
select the sewing needle, press the Delete key,
and delete it.
Then we need to adjust the weight back to the original value,
so that we can put this hat on the head of the virtual model.
Here we set the weight back to 9800.
After the simulation is started,
the plate collapses due to the effect of gravity.
When the plate collapses,
it is on the head of the virtual model.
At this time, we have a simple fur hat.
We just set the angle of the hat here.
Now we can set the angle of the hat here.
Because now we have 90 degrees of angle
on the front and the front,
so use the edit sewing tool
to set the folding angle of the sewing line here to 90.
After the control key is simulated,
it will form a sharp fold angle.
Because now the bending force is not particularly high,
so we can apply a new fabric to all the plates first.
Here we change the physical properties of the fabric
to Trim for Grain Leather.
This fabric has a particularly high bending force,
and its deformation rate is relatively low.
It is not easy to deform,
it is very good to maintain the folding effect we want.
And the feature of this fabric is that
it is not easy to fold.
For the top of the hat,
I originally did not plan to use the material called Full Grain Leather.
Of course, if you want it to have a very hard effect,
you can also put this fabric on the top of the hat.
In fact, the main condition of not easy to deform is
one is that the bending force is very high,
and the other is that the deformation rate is relatively low.
If I want to have a soft effect on this hat,
we can copy the fabric we just used,
then drag it to the top of the hat,
and reduce its bending force separately.
When we reduce the bending force,
because it is now in a state of bending,
it will collapse more strongly.
As the bending force increases,
it will become harder and harder.
In the past, our other fabrics
may lower the bending force of the oblique,
but because now this plate is a circular plate,
the fabric will be bent everywhere,
and the direction of the fabric is uncontrollable.
So here we can adjust the bending force of three of them to one value,
so that it can ensure that the bending performance on all directions is the same.
When the bending force is 100,
the fabric is not easy to bend,
so it looks like the hats of magicians in our real life,
as well as the dress hats,
because their hats are actually supported by a harder plate.
Then we can drag the hat
so that it can be worn on the head of the virtual model.
Then we can double-click the virtual model
to reduce its surface diameter a little,
so that the hat can be closer to the human body.
Then in the state of opening the model,
drag the hat,
we can slowly turn the side of the hat to the back.
If it is more troublesome to do this,
you can control A to select all the plates,
and then rotate it with the positioning ball.
We can also move the head of the model to the center of the model,
so that it can be placed like this.
And finally,
we can adjust the bending force of the hat to the other side.
In this way,
we can also adjust the bending force of the model.
And finally,
we can change the bending force of the model.
In my case,
the bending force of the model was 0 to 100.
So,
I can adjust the bending force of the model.
And this is the final result of the modeling.
We can see the difference between the two models.
So,
After we have adjusted it, we can reduce the particle diameter of all the panels of the hat
And then reduce the thickness of the collision
These are all to make the hat better simulated, and to make the curve smoother
Next, let's do the roll-up effect on the side
This effect also requires the use of a sewing needle
After using the sewing needle, we click on a point on the hat, and then click on a point on the side panel
After we have created it, we can start the simulation
This panel will automatically roll together
Therefore, we can first freeze the middle panel
So that it is not easy to receive the force of this roll-up
After that, we can use the editing sewing tool to select the created sewing line
In the right element editor, we can set the length of these two sewing lines
When we set its length to a relatively high value
For example, 50, which is 5 centimeters
It will naturally loosen
Then we can gradually adjust this value
If there are some mistakes when adding only one sewing line
We can add a few more sewing lines
After the installation is done, it is the same to change the length of its line
Through this method, we can make a lot of roll-up effects
Next, let's learn how to make the hat of a magician
First of all, we adjust the roll-up intensity to 100
So that it will not be affected by this fake seam
The hat of a magician is usually relatively high
So we also increase the height of the side panel
Then the hat of a magician has a feature
It may be a curved T-shape overall
The top is relatively large
So we can make the top of this circle a little larger
Because now the size is a certain difference
Plus the fabric itself is not easy to deform
So the middle will be arched
Because the side still wants to maintain its original size
That is to say, now we need to adjust the side panel accordingly
The first thing is that we want to match the length of the sewing line
So choose this edge
Then choose to change the length
We change the length of this edge to the total length close to the large circle
After the change
We have to choose to change it to both sides
Now our length is matched
But because the sides are sewn together
Finally it will form a fake corner
Now it is a sharp corner
So we have to change this edge to a curve
Let their fake corners be sewn together
As flat as possible
The second is the sewing line we just created
They may need to adjust the position or length again
If you just use the editor to adjust this curve
Sometimes the corners on the side are not necessarily two straight corners
Then we can use the edge curve tool
To create a curve on this edge
Then use the curve point to individually control
The curve close to this fake corner
Then we can drag this curve point
Let it form a straight corner with the side line next to it
So when our side lines are sewn together
It will be a flat corner
OK?
There it is
Now we just need to make the shark's claws
Look at this
Now we just need to trim this Cuba
We also need to trim this diffuser
Make some tiny holes
Some cut marks
Make a roundaros
And some loose Jesus
That's it
It is now made
Finally, the point and the tip is filming
Let's continue to apply the sealing
As you see
In this other cut